Finding Aid for Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies (University of Michigan) Records, 1892-2014
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Associate and Assistant Deans
  - Associate Dean for Student Recruitment and Support, 1981-1996
    - Topical Files
      - Race-Specific Fellowships, 1991-1992 (Box 185)
      - Racial Designation, 1991 (Box 185)
      - Rackham
        - Budget, 1992-1993 (Box 185)
        - Development Efforts, 1990 (Box 185)
        - Financial Reports, 1991-1992 (Box 185)
        - Financial Resources for Faculty, 1989-1991 (Box 185)
      - Rackham Dissertation/Thesis Grant, 1989-1992 (Box 185)
      - Rackham Fellowships Discretionary Fund, 1990-1992 (Box 185)
      - Rackham Merit Fellowship
        - Budget, 1983-1993 (Box 185)
        - Eligibility, 1995 (Box 185)
        - Faculty Review Committee, 1993-1994 (Box 185)
        - History, 1992 (Box 186)
        - Miscellaneous, 1993-1994 (Box 186)
        - Restructuring, 1992-1993 (Box 186)
      - Rackham/Regents Fellowship, 1989-1996 (Box 186)
      - Rackham Student Government, 1989 (Box 186)
      - Radcliffe/Ramsdell Fellowship, 1991-1992 (Box 186)
      - Ranking-National, 1990-1994 (Box 186)
      - Recruiting Efforts
        - 1984-86 (Box 186)
        - 1990-1991 (Box 186)
      - Recruiting Funding Requests, 1989-1992 (Box 186)
      - Recruitment and Retention Meetings, 1995; 2 folders (Box 186)
      - Research, Office of the Vice President for, 1994 (Box 186)
      - Research Partnership Program, 1989-1994 (Box 186)
      - Retention, 1978-1991 (Box 186)
      - Retreat on African American Students, 1995 (Box 186)
      - Search for Rackham Dean, 1995 (Box 186)
      - Socially Active Latino Student Association (SALSA), 1990 (Box 186)
      - Sokol Fellowship, 1993 (Box 192)
      - South Africa Initiative Office, 1993-1995 (Box 186)
      - State Name Exchange, 1979-85 (Box 186)
      - Student Recruitment and Support, Office of
        - General, 1986-89 (Box 186)
        - Fellowship Office Budget, 1988-89 (Box 186)
        - New Position, 1994 (Box 186)
        - Staff Retreat, 1993 (Box 186)
      - Student Relations Training Session, 1990-1991 (Box 186)
      - Students-Miscellaneous, 1993 (Box 192)
      - Students of Color of Rackham (SCOR), 1991-1996 (Box 186)
      - Summer Programs
        - Biological and Natural Sciences, 1990 (Box 186)
        - Humanities, 1989-1990 (Box 186)
        - ICPSR/ISR, 1987-1995 (Box 186)
        - Social Sciences, 1990 (Box 186)
        - Summer Institutes
          - 1993-1995 (Box 186)
          - 1990 (Box 186)
        - Summer Research Opportunity Program (SROP)
          - 1994-1996 (Box 186)
          - 1988-1993 (Box 186)
      - Texas A & M Study, 1990 (Box 186)
      - U.S.-Japanese Industry and Technology Management Training, 1991 (Box 186)
  - Assistant Dean for Program Support, 1989-1997
    The Assistant Dean for Program Support subseries (2 linear feet) contains files from the office within Rackham primarily responsible for budgeting recruitment and financial support programs, and supervising the administration of fellowships and recruitment initiatives. The Assistant Dean for Program Support reported to the Associate Dean for Student Recruitment and Support. The subseries consists mainly of internal correspondence and reports about financial support programs and budgeting. It also contains nine folders on the Scholarship/Fellowship Process Improvement Project, a campus-wide initiative to design and implement a new financial aid system.
    - Affirmative Action, 1996 (Box 188)
    - Alliance for Success, 1990-1994; 2 folders (Box 188)
    - Block Grant, 1989-1995 (Box 188)
    - Block Grant Report, 1996-1999 (Box 188)
    - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC)
      - Fellowship Program Study, 1993-1994 (Box 188)
      - Panel on Increased Access of Minorities to Graduate School, 1994-1996 (Box 188)
    - Committee to Review Programs in Minority Affairs and Services, 1991-1992 (Box 188)
    - Council on Graduate Schools (CGS)/Peterson's Award for Innovation in the Recruitment of Minority Graduate Students, 1994-1995 (Box 188)
    - Federal Policies on Minority Fellowships, 1990-1991 (Box 188)
    - Fellowship Status Reports, 1989-1990 (Box 188)
    - Fellowships Budget, 1992-1994 (Box 188)
    - Florida A&M, 1992-1996 (Box 188)
    - GOAPAST, 1996-1997 (Box 188)
    - Graduate Experience Project (for women in engineering), 1996; 2 folders (Box 188)
    - GRE Locator Service, 1991 (Box 188)
    - Patricia Roberts Harris Fellowship Program, 1990-1996; 2 folders (Box 188)
    - Institute for Recruitment of Teachers, 1990-1993 (Box 188)
    - International Travel Grants, 1991-1997 (Box 188)
    - Dolores Zohrab Liebmann Fund, 1995-1996 (Box 188)
    - Martin Luther King Day, 1991-1993 (Box 188)
    - Ronald E. McNair Postbaccalaureate Achievement Program, 1998-1999; 2 folders (Box 188)
    - Merging of Michigan Minority Merit and Rackham Minority Fellowship Programs, 1990 (Box 188)
    - Minority Equity, Office of, 1990-1992 (Box 188)
    - Minority Fellowship Report, 1991 (Box 188)
    - Morehouse College, 1992-1994 (Box 188)
    - Native American Eligibility, 1992-1994 (Box 188)
    - Opportunity Funds-History, 1995 (Box 188)
    - Probation List Process, 1991 (Box 188)
    - Project 1000, 1990-1992 (Box 188)
    - Racial Designation, 1990-1991 (Box 188)
    - Rackham Executive Board Subcommittee "New Faces,", 1996-1997 (Box 188)
    - Rackham First Year Fellowships, 1996 (Box 188)
    - Rackham Merit Fellowship
      - General, 1991-1993 (Box 189)
      - Candidates' Reception, 1991-1997 (Box 189)
      - Eligibility, 1992-1996 (Box 189)
      - Historical, 1979-1991 (Box 189)
      - Report, 1996 (Box 189)
      - Restructuring, 1992 (Box 189)
    - Recruiting, 1991-1993 (Box 189)
    - Recruitment/Retention Plan, 1993 (Box 189)
    - Research Partnership Program, 1991-1995 (Box 189)
    - Scholarship/Fellowship Process Improvement Project
      - Aid Identification (AIDID) Work Group, 1995 (Box 189)
      - Architecture and Telecommunications Work Group, 1994-1995 (Box 189)
      - Budget, 1994 (Box 189)
      - Planning Group, 1991-1995 (Box 189)
      - Process and Policy Work Group, 1994-1995 (Box 189)
      - Proposal, 1992 (Box 189)
      - Report, 1992 (Box 189)
      - Roll-Out Meetings, 1995 (Box 189)
      - Miscellaneous, 1991-1995 (Box 189)
    - Students of Color of Rackham (SCOR), 1990-1996 (Box 189)
    - SCOR/Graduate Employees Organization (GEO), 1992 (Box 189)
    - Summer Institutes, 1990-1996 (Box 189)
    - Summer Research Opportunity Program (SROP), 1990-1993 (Box 189)
    - SROP Lead Institution, 1990 (Box 189)
    - Undergraduate Research Programs and College of Engineering, 1994 (Box 189)
  - Miscellaneous Associate and Assistant Deans
    The Miscellaneous Associate and Assistant Deans subseries (0.5 linear feet) consists of a small amount of correspondence and reports from various associate and assistant deans in Rackham, including the Associate Dean for Faculty Programs and the Assistant Dean for Academic Programs.
    - Academic Programs Correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 190)
    - Affirmative Action, 1988-1993 (Box 190)
    - Committee on Course Criteria, 1979-86 (Box 190)
    - D'Arms Award, 1994-1995 (Box 190)
    - Expense Statistics, 1982-1993 (Box 190)
    - Faculty Programs Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 190)
    - Honors Mentorship Program, 1988-89 (Box 190)
    - Integrative Graduate Education and Research Training (IGERT) Program, 1997 (Box 190)
    - International Graduate Student Instructors (IGSI), 1996-1997 (Box 190)
    - Michigan Journalism Fellows, 1987-1994 (Box 190)
    - Miscellaneous Handouts and Forms, 1978-1992 (Box 190)
    - Pilot Secondary Science Teacher (SST)/Postdoc (PD) Exchange Program, 1997 (Box 190)
    - Program Evaluation Procedures, 1982-86 (Box 190)
    - Rackham Fellowships, 1997 (Box 190)
    - Rackham Pre-Doctoral Dinners, 1987-1999 (Box 190)
    - Remote Sensing Spatial Analysis Laboratory for Interdisciplinary Teaching and Research, 1997 (Box 190)
    - Student Records Policies, 1978-1991 (Box 190)
    - Unit Assessment, 1994-1995 (Box 190)
- Research Records
  The Research Records series consists of a variety of material documenting grant funded research, supported directly by the graduate school or by external funds administered by Rackham. The series is divided into a number of subseries based on chronology, type of grant and academic division. The series includes summaries of research activities; Project files that may include grant applications, progress or final reports, review materials, correspondence, and administrative records.
  - Summary and Administrative Information
    The Summary and Administrative Information subseries consists of such overview material as is available for Rackham sponsored research after 1953. Two published volumes supplement the material in this series documenting activity prior to 1953. Most helpful are the reports by divisional groups.
    - Faculty Research Grants, 1937-1977
      - 1937-1945 (Box 19)
      - 1947-1958, 3 folders (Box 19)
      - 1958-1966, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Fall 1965, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Spring 1966, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Fall 1966, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Spring 1967, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Fall 1967 (Box 20)
      - Spring 1968 (Box 20)
      - Spring 1969 (Box 20)
      - Fall 1969 (Box 20)
      - 1970 (Box 20)
      - 1971-1977, 7 folders (Box 21)
    - Faculty Research Fellowships, 1965-1969; 5 folders (Box 21)
    - Research Funds
      - 1953-1956 (Box 22)
      - Spring 1957 (Box 22)
      - Fall 1957 (Box 22)
      - Spring 1958 (Box 22)
      - Fall 1958 (Box 22)
      - Spring 1959 (Box 22)
      - Fall 1959 (Box 22)
      - Fall 1965 (Box 22)
      - Spring 1966 (Box 22)
      - Fall 1966 (Box 22)
    - Divisional Groups
      - Divisional Organizations and Meetings (Box 22)
      - Group I: Physical Sciences, 1938-1959; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Group II. Biological Sciences, 1936-1961; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Group III. Language and Literature, 1936-1961; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Group IV: Social Sciences, 1936-1961; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - Group IV: Social Sciences, 1936-1961 (Box 23)
      - Group V: Fine Arts, 1940-1961; 2 folders (Box 23)
      - Group VI: Museums, 1936-1939 (Box 23)
      - Group VII: Health Sciences, 1944-1961; 2 folders (Box 23)
        (after 1940 Health Sciences designated as Group VI)
    - Research Funds, 1936-1940 (Box 23)
    - Development Grants, 1976-1978; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - Project Files
    Project Files represent the extant material documenting each individual project funded through the Graduate School. Typical files contain a grant proposal, and progress or final reports. Administrative papers (letter of authorization, invoices, detailed financial statements, etc.) are generally not included in the file, although such items become more common as files become more current. Project Files are divided into two units, Major Grant Programs and Minor Grant Programs. Placement of a particular grant program is arbitrary, generally based on the number of grants awarded and the years documented. Arrangement within each unit is alphabetical, by name of grant program. Each grant program is usually arranged by grant number, the two major exceptions being Rackham Publication Grants, which are arranged alphabetically by the name of the grant recipient.
    - Major Grant Programs
      - Faculty Research Fund
        - Projects #1-53 and unnumbered (project initiation dates), 1927-1928 (Box 23)
        - Projects #54-229, 1928-1932 (Box 24)
        - Projects #230-372, 1932-1935 (Box 25)
        - Projects #373-558, 1935-1940 (Box 26)
        - Projects #559-724, 1940-1948 (Box 27)
        - Projects #725-849, 1948-1951 (Box 28)
        - Projects #850-999, 1951-1955 (Box 29)
        - Projects #1000 (13000)-1152 (31938), 1955-1958 (Box 30)
        - Projects #1153 (31939)-1301 (13301), 1958-1962 (Box 31)
        - Projects FRF 1302 (13302)-FRF, 1432 (13432), 1962-1967 (Box 32)
        - Projects FRF 1433 (13433)-FRG, 1514 (135014), 1967-1972 (Box 33)
        - Projects FRG 135015-FRG 1514 (135014), 1967-1972 (Box 34)
        - Miscellaneous FRF Grants (duplicate numbers)
          - FRF 116; FRF 130; FRF 132-FRF 140, circa 1972 (Box 34)
      - Faculty Research, Rackham Fund Grants
        - Alphabetical Sequence, 1935-1936
          - Archeological Expedition to Seleucia (Box 34)
          - Archeological Expedition in Egypt (Box 34)
          - Brian Psychology (Box 34)
          - Cancer Research (Box 34)
          - Child Study (Box 34)
          - Dental Research (Box 34)
          - FERA Freshman College Reference Books (Box 34)
          - Fresh Air Camp (Box 34)
          - Governmental Research (Box 34)
          - Heart Station Research (Box 34)
          - Hospitalization (Box 34)
          - Infantile Paralysis (Box 34)
          - Lip Reading Education (Box 34)
          - Metabolism Research (Box 34)
          - Michigan Indian History (Box 34)
          - Nuclear Research (Box 34)
          - Optical cancer Research (Box 34)
          - Post-graduate Medicine (Box 34)
          - Research Fellowship (Box 34)
          - Research in Rickets (Box 34)
          - Research in Surgery (Box 34)
          - Social Work Building and Site (Box 34)
          - South African Astronomical (Box 34)
          - Syphilis Treatment (Box 34)
          - Therapeutic Pool (Box 34)
          - Visual research (Box 34)
        - Numerical Sequence
          - Project R1-R12 (project initiation dates), 1935-1936 (Box 34)
          - Project R13-R71, 1936-1939 (Box 35)
          - Project R72-R147, 1939-1943 (Box 36)
          - Project R148-R261, 1943-1961 (Box 37)
          - Project R263-R391, 1951-1956 (Box 38)
          - Project R392-R533, 1957-1960 (Box 39)
          - Project R534 (35935)-R684 (37942), 1960-1964 (Box 40)
          - Project R685 (37943)-R818 (33829), 1964-1967 (Box 41)
          - Project R819 (33830)-FRR928 (332780), 1967-1970 (Box 42)
          - Project FRR929 (332790)-FRR1005 (360413), 1970-1971 (Box 43)
          - Project FRR1006 (360246)-FRR1065 (360413), 1971-1972 (Box 44)
          - Project FRR1066 (360414)-FRR1106 (360608), 1972 (Box 45)
          - Project FRR 360609-FRR 360681 (Box 53)
          - Project FRR 360682-FRR 360699 (Box 54)
          - Project(Phoenix)
            - 361619 (Box 54)
            - 361685 (Box 54)
          - Project FRF 386001-FRF 386025 (Box 54)
          - Project FRR 387001-FRR 387029 (Box 54)
          - Project FRR 387031-FRR 387106 (Box 55)
          - Project FRR 387107-FRR 387141 (Box 56)
          - Project FRR 387142-FRR 387171 (Box 56)
          - Project FRR 387172-FRR 387231 (Box 57)
          - Project FRR 387232-FRR 387297 and FRG 1485 (134850) (Box 58)
          - Project FRR 387298-FRR 387325 and FRG 1485 (134850) (Box 59)
          - Project FRR 135033-FRR 135052 (gaps) (Box 63)
          - Project FRR 387149-FRR 387374 (gaps) (Box 63)
          - Project FRR 387375-FRR 387433 (gaps) (Box 64)
          - Project FRR 387444-FRR 387499 (Box 65)
          - Project FRR 387501-FRR 387557 (Box 66)
          - Project FRR 387558-FRR 387612 (Box 67)
          - Project FRR 387601-FRR 387658 (Box 68)
          - Project FRR 387659-FRR 387724 (Box 69)
          - Project FRR 387725-FRR 387802 (Box 70)
          - Project FRR 387803-FRR 387873 (Box 71)
          - Project FRR 387874-FRR 387899 (Box 72)
      - Faculty Research, U.S. Government (Federal)
        - Project NFRR1 (31660)-FRF60 (31719), 1967-1968 (Box 45)
        - Project FRF61 (31720)-360138, 1968-1973 (Box 46)
        - Project 360139-360159, 1973 (Box 47)
      - National Science Foundation
        - Project NSF1-NSF85, 1960-1965 (Box 47)
        - Project NSF86-NSF151 (010056), 1965-1971 (Box 48)
      - Rackham Equipment Grants
        - Projects #1-99, 1953-1956 (Box 48)
        - Projects #100-194, 1956-1964 (Box 49)
      - Rackham Publications Grants, circa 1940-1970
        - A-H (Box 49)
        - I-W (Box 50)
        - X-Z (Box 51)
        - Contingency Grants, 1967-1969; 2 folders (Box 51)
    - Minor Grant Programs
      - Cosgrove Fund (3 grants), 1962-1963 (Box 51)
      - CBS Fund (4 grants), 1963-1964 (Box 51)
      - Faculty Research, Special Grants (86 grants), 1955-1967 (Box 51)
      - Michigan Alumni Fund (70 grants), 1954-1964 (Box 52)
      - National Institute of Health (12 grants), 1967-1969 (Box 52)
      - Office of Education (U.S. Government) (7 grants), 1967 (Box 52)
      - United States Public Health Service (11 grants), 1963-1969 (Box 52)
  - Faculty Research Grants, 1970-1992
    The Faculty Grants, 1970-1992 subseries (3.5 linear feet) documents the grant application process for faculty, including the actual application materials, correspondence, review materials, and committee rating sheets from 1970 to 1992. The 1996 Accession contains information on the NEH Summer Stipend, Faculty Research Grants, and Faculty International Grants. The Research and International Grants are organized by grant number. In order to increase access to the data, indexes have been provided to both sets of grants which includes the grant number, followed by the applicant name and departmental affiliation. The indexes are located at the end of the finding aid.
    - General
      - Board of Governors Proposals / Correspondence, 1986 (Box 135)
      - General, 1985-1986 (Box 135)
      - Statistics, 1983-1989 (Box 135)
    - Faculty--General
      - Winter 1987
        - General (Box 135)
        - Division One (Box 135)
        - Division Two (Box 135)
        - Division Three (Box 135)
        - Division Four (Box 135)
      - General, Winter 1988 (Box 135)
      - Fall 1988
        - General (Box 135)
        - Division One (Box 135)
        - Division Two (Box 135)
        - Division Three (Box 135)
        - Division Four (Box 135)
      - Winter 1989
        - General (Box 135)
        - Division One (Box 135)
        - Division Two (Box 135)
        - Division Three (Box 135)
        - Division Four (Box 135)
      - Fall 1990
        - Division One (Box 135)
        - Division Two (Box 135)
        - Division Three (Box 135)
        - Division Four (Box 135)
      - Winter 1990
        - General (Box 135)
        - Division One (Box 135)
        - Division Two (Box 135)
        - Division Three (Box 135)
        - Division Four (Box 135)
      - Fall 1991
        - General (Box 136)
        - Division One, 2 folders (Box 136)
        - Division Two, 2 folders (Box 136)
        - Division Three (Box 136)
        - Division Four, 2 folders (Box 136)
      - Winter 1991
        - General (Box 136)
        - Division One, 2 folders (Box 136)
        - Division Two (Box 136)
        - Division Three (Box 136)
        - Division Four (Box 136)
      - Fall 1992
        - General (Box 136)
        - Division One (Box 136)
        - Division Two, 2 folders (Box 136)
        - Division Three, 2 folders (Box 136)
        - Division Four, 2 folders (Box 136)
      - Winter 1992
        - General (Box 136)
        - Division One, 2 folders (Box 136)
        - Division Two (Box 136)
        - Division Three (2 folders0 (Box 136)
        - Division Four (Box 136)
    - Faculty--NEH Summer Stipend
      - 1970-1971 (Box 137)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 137)
      - 1974 (Box 137)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 137)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 137)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 137)
      - 1981 (Box 137)
      - (missing), 1982 (Box 137)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 137)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 137)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 137)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 137)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 137)
    - Faculty International Grants
      (See Index to Grants)
      - Reports, 1986-1988 (Box 137)
      - 135053-135058 (Box 137)
      - 135059-135065 (Box 137)
      - 135066-135072 (Box 137)
      - 135073-135079 (Box 137)
      - 135081-135085 (Box 137)
      - 135086-135093 (Box 137)
      - 135094-135099 (Box 137)
      - 135101-135105 (Box 137)
      - 135106-135111 (Box 137)
      - 135112-135118 (Box 137)
      - 135119-135126 (Box 137)
      - 135127-135133 (Box 137)
      - 135134-135138 (Box 137)
    - Faculty Research Grants
      - 386000-386003 (Box 137)
      - 386004-386008 (Box 137)
      - 386009-386012 (Box 137)
      - 386013-386016 (Box 137)
      - 386017-386020 (Box 137)
      - 386021-386024 (Box 137)
      - 386025-386028 (Box 138)
      - 386029-386032 (Box 138)
      - 386033-386036 (Box 138)
      - 386037-386040 (Box 138)
      - 386042-386045 (Box 138)
      - 386046-386049 (Box 138)
      - 386050-386053 (Box 138)
      - 386054-386057 (Box 138)
      - 386058-386061 (Box 138)
      - 386062-386065 (Box 138)
      - 386066-386069 (Box 138)
      - 386070-386073 (Box 138)
      - 386074-386077 (Box 138)
      - 386078-386081 (Box 138)
      - 386082-386085 (Box 138)
      - 386086-386089 (Box 138)
      - 386090-386093 (Box 138)
      - 386094-386097 (Box 138)
      - 386098-386101 (Box 138)
      - 386102-386105 (Box 138)
      - 386106-386109 (Box 138)
      - 386110-386113 (Box 138)
      - 386114-386117 (Box 138)
      - 386118-386121 (Box 138)
      - 386122-386125 (Box 138)
      - 386126-386129 (Box 138)
      - 386130-386133 (Box 138)
      - 386134-386137 (Box 138)
      - 386138-386141 (Box 138)
      - 386142-386145 (Box 138)
      - 386146-386149 (Box 138)
      - 386151-386154 (Box 138)
      - 386155-386158 (Box 138)
      - 386159-386162 (Box 139)
      - 386163-386166 (Box 139)
      - 386168-386171 (Box 139)
      - 386172-386175 (Box 139)
      - 386176-386179 (Box 139)
      - 386180-386183 (Box 139)
      - 386184-386187 (Box 139)
      - 386189-386192 (Box 139)
      - 386193-386194 (Box 139)
      - (386195-387942 missing) (Box 139)
      - 387901-387906 (Box 139)
      - 387907-387913 (Box 139)
      - 387915-387918 (Box 139)
      - 387919-387924 (Box 139)
      - 387925-387929 (Box 139)
      - 387931-387942 (Box 139)
      - 387943-387948 (Box 139)
      - 387949-387953 (Box 139)
      - 387954-387957 (Box 139)
      - 387958-387962 (Box 139)
      - 387963-387966 (Box 139)
      - 387967-387972 (Box 139)
      - 387973-387976 (Box 139)
      - 387977-387981 (Box 139)
      - 387982-387985 (Box 139)
      - 387986-387989 (Box 139)
      - 387992-387996 (Box 139)
      - 387997-387999 (Box 139)
- University Units, 1952-2008
  The University Units series consists largely of printed materials (brochures, annual reports, etc.) and correspondence and reports on the teaching, curriculum, and funding of graduate courses. The series is subdivided chronologically (reflecting the multiple accession in which materials were received) but there is temporal overlap among the subseries. Each of the subseries is arranged in five sub-subseries: Branch Campuses (Dearborn and Flint), Centers, Institutes, Interdepartmental/Interdisciplinary Programs (IDPs), and Schools and Colleges. The IDPs subseries is particularly interesting for the light it sheds on the emphasis on interdisciplinary education and research.
  - 1952-1985
    - Branch Campuses
      - Dearborn
        - 1966-1969 (Box 85)
        - 1970-1974 (Box 85)
        - 1975-1977 (Box 85)
        - 1978-1979 (Box 85)
        - 1980-1985 (Box 85)
      - Flint, 1972-1977 (Box 85)
    - Centers
      - Center for Afro-American and African Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 85)
      - Center for the Continuing Education of Women, 1975-1983 (Box 85)
      - Center for Human Growth and Development
        - General, 1980-1982 (Box 85)
        - Children's Center, 1979-1985 (Box 85)
      - Center for Japanese Studies, 1976-1978 (Box 85)
      - Center for Medieval, Renaissance, and Reformation Studies, 1983 (Box 85)